The reverse zoo.
Don't feed the animals.
Boys are outside, um,
so we can fit our two
new friends in here today.
Got a little bit of a
boma built on the outside
of the cage, so we know
there's hippo around.
We know there's
elephants around.
And we really do have to
make sure that we're safe.
The plan is for the
outsiders to climb
on top of the rage cage
if danger approaches.
In the distance,
there are noises
that we can't identify.
You never know what's out there.
Seriously, what the?
After battling for
survival... A lion!
Holy!
What!
...in a post-apocalyptic
land... You wanna hold this?
Oh,
-Oh!
-Ah!
...for 25 days.
If I'm gonna die, I'm
gonna die fighting.
Definitely got him!
It's dinner time!
Yeah, buddy!
All right, guys, let's do this.
The three remaining
teams pushed further north
toward their escape...
Oh, my gosh!
Ready to get out of this place.
Back to civilization.
...targeting the last
collection of viable waterholes,
eight miles from the
edge of civilization...
Oh, thank God! It
looks like it opens up.
That's just weird.
This is a big old cage!
...with only an abandoned
cage on a failed game reserve
to call home.
What is this?
-Look!
-Oh, my God!
Two teams join forces.
Welcome to the Rage Cage!
What are we walking into?
As Teal scored another
win for her team... Whoo!
Yeah!
...and after discovering a
nearby slaughterhouse...
Oh, creepy as hell!
Like a butcher shop.
...Wes and Stee reached
the last source of
water on the map.
Hey!
People keep showing
up at our doorstep.
But now, for the
first time ever...
There's no one
coming to save us.
We're on our own.
...there is no rescue in sight.
There's no trucks.
There's no helicopters.
They must forge their own
escape out of the wasteland
on Day 35.
We're going on
a little adventure.
That's gonna be an
arduous trek through that.
Stee said he saw some
sort of structure on the way in,
so we're just gonna go
up, see what materials
we can pick up.
We've got to escape
at the end of the week,
we all know we're gonna
need a lot of energy for that,
so until we're putting food
on the plate pretty regularly,
that's gonna be our number
one objective every day.
So whenever you need
to take breaks, guys,
like, take breaks, it is hot, we
don't have any water with us,
so just be smart.
Four weeks in, and
right from the beginning,
it's always been surreal to me
that I'm walking around naked
in one of the harshest
environments on the planet...
from the animals
that wanna eat you,
from the heat that
wants to kill you.
There are all the same
risks, except we're more tired,
we're more dehydrated,
we have less fuel
than when we did
when we were coming in.
That becomes a real problem,
especially when you're facing
what could be a
really arduous escape.
Still Africa, still
the apocalypse.
Oh!
The reason I'm doing
this... it covers up your scent,
breaks up your contrast.
Just grab some waterhole mud
full of elephant dung, fish
guts, God knows what else.
We need a big score.
We have a lot of
people here now.
We have eight people.
That's eight mouths to feed.
That's eight hungry
stomachs and a week left.
We need one big kill.
If not, we're gonna end
up having people tapping
and we're too close to the
end to let any of that happen.
Hopefully, I can come
back with some food
and get some
protein in our bellies.
All right.
It's looking like I'm coming
up on some water over here.
But just from here, I can see
that there's action down here.
I got new prints.
I got wildebeests.
I got impala. I got
one, two, three.
I got four game
trails all converging,
wrapping around this guy.
And I got natural
cover right here.
This is perfect!
This is an absolute,
unrelenting hellscape.
It is the most temperamental
place I have ever been
on planet Earth.
You know, from heat
stroke to hypothermia
to things that wanna eat
you to, you know, there being
such very few calories walking
around that we have access to.
So that's what
makes this challenge
the hardest challenge
I've been on yet.
And we gotta get out
of this Hell on Earth
all by ourselves.
We are not being rescued.
I already built up a
pretty good blind area.
I've cut down a lot of foliage.
-Oh, is this it?
-Yep.
Wow.
-Look at that!
-Holy [bleep!
So was this a slaughterhouse?
Yeah, this looks
like where they would
haul up the animals,
use the pulley system,
drag them up, drain 'em,
gut 'em, so they'd be able
to hose them down and
be able to work the meat.
It's pretty wild.
Once part of a large
hunting reserve,
this compound was
used as a supply outpost
and processing station
for large game animals.
Yeah.
-Wow.
-It's pretty intense.
They cut the giraffes
here and everything.
Yeah.
This slaughterhouse, it's
just the weirdest feeling,
the most creepy,
apocalyptic, desperate place.
But just watch out,
like, the slightest scratch
on something in here is like
tetanus waiting to happen.
Yeah, yeah. I'm
gonna go in here next.
You reckon this, uh,
is worth taking back?
If you catch some
good meat, yes.
Yeah?
Awesome.
These last few days
have been a roller coaster.
We've got so many different
things going on in our big boma
and so many different
people handling things.
It's definitely
different and require
a lot of adjustments.
Waz!
I got the panel puller
and I got some cordage.
What are your thoughts
on the wriggly tin?
-Thoughts on the what?
-Wriggly tin.
Yeah, bring them.
Good job, buddy.
Any of that interest you?
Let's go.
Take that as a no.
-What's this?
-That is wire.
Like, it's all ripped
up in pieces.
The metal's only
a little rusted.
You could use it for fishing.
Huh.
-Yeah, we gonna...
-Yeah.
Just drag it like a grid line,
-like a grid line.
-It's gonna be hard work
to get it, but, once it's
down there, we roll it out.
And then, like I said, eight
people... eight people can
move, you know, 10 feet
of chicken wire a piece.
There's like a long metal mesh
that we're gonna be able to
use to maybe dredge through
or cordon off a section,
maybe try and get some catfish
into a more manageable area.
I could probably drag
this all the way back too.
Ooh!
The corrugated iron
would certainly give us
some more shade during
the day, which would allow us
to escape this heat,
but it would also set up
wind walls or firewalls to
keep in the heat at night.
Yeah.
Whoa!
All right!
Throughout this
entire challenge,
when there is absolutely
no resources around,
it's literally life or death
without the implementation
of the man made materials.
And so this is our
lifeline right now.
Oh, my God.
Honey, we're home!
You guys brought
back a whole house.
I look over the corner,
and what do I see?
I see the team
hauling a building back.
We can use that
for the rage cage.
All of these little things,
these things that people
call trash, are treasure to us,
and we're gonna
treat them as such.
Welcome back!
Come sit down. We got water.
Good job. That's a lot.
Shade, shade, shade. Water.
You want some help with that?
I'd rather you sit down.
I'm just gonna do
some stuff here,
just for the clock and the sun.
We did bring back a
lot of corrugated steel
from the butcher's house,
and that will be resourceful
for many things.
Right now, the best
use of it is blocking
this intense afternoon sun.
I'm doing it. Yeah, no problem.
I don't need any help.
I'm serious.
Even though I have
a large personality,
I am not somebody
who's extremely sociable.
I've been doing pretty
good for the most part of this,
but these last few days have
been absolutely exhausting
and mentally spent.
Well, thanks Teal.
I'm sure at night
we won't want it,
but perhaps now it's good.
So what you guys doing?
We're gonna stretch
out chicken wire
So it unrolls that way. Cool.
We got this chicken wire
from up at the slaughterhouse,
and we're just gonna
unroll it and walk it out there,
pull it around
through the water,
and just sort of
see how it acts,
see what the fish do.
I think it's got a big hole.
Like, it's a lot of
holes in the middle.
Yeah, we got some
rugged parts here.
You wanna do a test run with it?
Absolutely. If we
come in right here
at an angle and just quarantine
this piece of the pond off...
Measuring over 60 feet,
the rusty chicken wire will be
stretched across the
narrowest part of the pond
and down to the mud floor.
The team must work in
unison to corral the fish
toward the shore while blocking
the gaps and holes in the wire.
All right, who's
leading this expedition?
So Waz is just heading that way.
Everyone simply
just follow me across.
And then we're gonna
spread out along this thing.
There's eight people here now.
It means more mouths to feed.
But, in a situation like this,
it can be a total advantage
because, you know, you
got more hands on deck.
It's getting harder.
I feel like I'm dragging it.
-Yeah, keep going.
-Yeah, drag's good.
Yeah, that's how it should feel.
We're trying to
let the net just stay
-right on the ground level.
-OK.
I'll let it drag a little.
You guys wanna cut it in?
We're going to
start bringing it in.
Yeah.
Sorry, I'm having to move
mine through the mud
-'cause it's in the mud.
-It needs to be
-in the mud.
-That's what I mean.
So I'm having to push
it from the bottom.
I'm using my foot.
Kind of gotta stomp
the whole thing.
I'm finding huge gaps down here.
There's some holes in
the line, in the net here.
There's a hole, yep, there.
I think from here, guys,
we do one thing at a time.
-We go slow, we do it right.
-Absolutely.
-I got swirls in front of me.
-...Oh, yeah.
Catfish right there.
Yep, yep.
All of a sudden, I
can see the turbulence
on top of the water
just move a little bit.
Little splashes
and little kicks.
For me, it just turned
it real serious, real fast.
-Yeah.
-...Hang on, hang on, hang on!
Oh, they are coming!
I've lost the hole.
-Hang on.
-Everyone pause.
Everyone good?
Oh, this hole's getting bigger.
-Keep it going.
-Yeah, I'm just tryna
hold the hole
together and push it
-through the mud.
-I say we keep push...
It's all right, that's all
right, that's all right.
Just one... just
one. Keep that gap.
Do you want me... you want
me to switch... switch out?
Yeah, I think you're gonna
have a better chance.
It was... and I
didn't wanna do that.
The fish, they're
literally jumping
over the chicken wire right now.
You know, there's
a lot going on.
We see food leaving,
and tensions are rough.
-Hold on, hold on!
-Hold on!
Trying close this
gap underwater.
I can't close this
Hold on. Who's... just like
one commander on movement.
Who's comma... who's the
commander of movements?
When we move in, pull towards
me so I can push it over here.
-Yeah.
-That way our net gets
smaller and we
tighten the hole here.
I'm catching whatever
the comes through here
-if they try.
-Nice.
I got him. Oh, grab him!
Yes!
My fingers are
getting torn to shreds.
Yep, I feel you.
Oh!
Jumped right through that hole.
Why... Wes, go try
to grab, come on!
Oh! There's a hole.
There's a hole by
your foot, Steven.
I got it! I got it!
-Yes!
-Come on!
Oh, it's a big one!
As we funnel up to the bank,
we're seeing fish
fighting and flopping
and just coming
right out of the water.
Hold up your side..
The adrenaline is
just rushing through us.
It's here.
No!
Gosh!
Come on!
It's here.
Here.
No!
Got one.
Hey, I'm on.
No!
All right, is!
No, he's not!
I got a huge one! ...We're gonna
take him, we're gonna take him.
I'm in his jaw.
I just need somebody
to back me up.
I'm there. I'm
right on top of you.
You gotta have the gill!
-I got it.
-Yes!
-Yeah, girl!
-Back up.
-Get to shore.
-Get to shore... oh! Oh!
-Oh!
There you go... I got it
right here, blocking the path.
-Blocking the path.
-That's OK.
-Throw him.
-There you go.
-Yes!
Got him.
-Whoo!
-Yes!
Yes!
Oh, yes!
-Whoo!
-Yes!
Teal, get up here!
Yes!
Yeah!
Pretty grub. Look
at these guys, man!
What does this make?
One, two, three,
four, five, six?
-I think there's eight.
-Seven, eight, yeah.
We caught eight fish,
and there were eight of us.
So it's very serendipitous.
So how do you grab this?
-Like this, look.
-There?
Reach all the way
inside his mouth.
-This way?
-...Yeah, they're not gon' bite you.
OK.
A collective effort to
put food on the table,
and we've come up with the win,
and what a beautiful win it is.
Never caught a catfish,
never held a catfish.
Epic.
I feel like I succeeded,
even if it wasn't
an individual effort.
Teammates to win,
and that's all that counts.
This is a ridiculous
amount of food.
We might have to
hang a couple up
-and smoke 'em overnight.
-An appropriate amount of food.
We can smoke 'em
right on our rack, too.
We gotta get to work
gutting these things pronto.
We got some work ahead of us.
Hey, I'll start gutting.
Yeah, I'm with you, buddy.
Everybody's working,
doing their jobs.
We got Teal filleting.
We got Joe over
here stringing fillets.
We're gonna smoke
those for tomorrow.
That way we're gonna
have a fillet each tonight.
We're gonna have a
huge hunk of fish tonight.
And we're gonna have backup
fish for the next couple days.
I've never seen a
whole fish smoked.
Yeah.
I'm not sure that
that is gonna work.
Cooking a whole
fish takes longer.
If you don't fillet it, it
takes longer for the heat
to evenly cook all of the flesh.
Anything that thick
is a risk for spoilage.
I think with that
smoky flavor, dude,
and we'll just let them
simmer all day tomorrow.
All right, yeah.
We'll see.
-Wow!
-Look at this Literally a tray of meat.
Divine!
-Amazing!
-Yeah.
Oh, my God!
It just goes to show that, like,
you can be having the
worst day in the world,
-and it can turn itself around.
-Incredible!
That was some tribal
fishing right there.
-It was.
-Yeah.
Everyone slept really,
really well last night,
because we have full
bellies. But we woke up to this.
Just having the clouds
has probably dropped
the temperature 15 degrees.
We were up at
Slaughterhouse yesterday.
There's still some stuff up
there we can bring back down.
-Yeah.
-We can start doing some sort of shelter.
And we need to put
a roof on the shelter.
All right, ladies.
We'll be back.
The only other day I
remember like this was
the day before
the torrential rain.
Oh, my God!
This is really hard.
I can suffer.
But I'm only human.
And that worries me a little bit
because we're in a
very precarious position
with our shelter.
We might be secure and
safe from outside animals,
but we are way less secure
with absolutely zero
waterproof shelter
when it comes to the weather.
Well, lemme just have a look
-what this is here real quick.
-Yeah.
This looks like it used
to be a really nice place.
-Is that solid enough?
-What?
Is that solid enough?
I've never been here before,
so I just wanna put
my eyes on everything.
Yes.
Could be food tucked
up in them cracks,
snakes, lizards.
There's no telling
what happened here,
but I wish these
walls could talk.
Good.
Started digging the trench
around the Rage Cage,
and... I'm gonna make
this, uh, as deep as possible.
And then I wanna
run it all the way back
behind the boma.
And then same
for the other side.
It's becoming more and
more obvious that this rain
is moving in faster
than we expected.
We have no idea how
much rain is coming,
so we really do need
to have our plan in place.
The trench is just gonna make it
so that we don't get flooding.
Everybody's got a
different comfort zone.
I know mine is not getting wet.
OK.
We brought a wedge
that's also epic for digging.
OK, come on, grab
your wedge and jump in.
-Do whatever you want.
-Oh, no, no, no.
I'm just saying for
you as an option, like,
if it really helped
us in digging,
it's an alternative option
if you wanted to
try it at any point.
If you have a great idea,
then my personal preference
-is you just do it.
-OK.
I'm not much for...
I'll just leave you to it.
-...advisement.
-I will just leave you to it.
I get it, I get it. There
might be a better way
to do it, but the best
way to show that is to...
No, I'm not saying
there's a better way.
I'm just offering an
alternative if you needed it.
I made a couple of
suggestions to Teal.
Unfortunately, they
weren't taken very well.
And, in this apocalyptic
wasteland of a place,
your stress response, your
fight and flight response,
every single day is at
its absolute maximum.
Let's just be quiet
-for the next two hours, then.
-Nice.
But what the is this?
No one really wants to
get their head snapped off.
Oh, nice!
We are coming back with
a boatload of sheet metal.
Just in time, 'cause
the rain is coming.
One, two, three.
Anywhere in here.
-Right here?
-Yeah.
We decided it was time to go
ahead and assemble the roof.
And so, you know,
I'm an engineer,
and we're gonna make
an interior roof for the cage.
Wes's plan calls for
two scavenged poles
to be placed through
the grid of the cage,
one slightly higher
than the other.
Then layering on
sheets of corrugated steel
to create a pitch-roof
that redirects water
out one side of the cage.
Is that... the left one?
Down, down, down,
and over, over.
-This way.
-There you go.
-Yeah.
-Here?
-Let's go right here.
-Yeah, sure.
-All right.
We also have to start
the wriggly tin at the back
if we want the
appropriate overlap.
Yeah, I got you. I got you.
-One, two, three, four.
-Yeah.
So we can actually get
another one on that side
if you want to cover the fire.
Wes is amazing.
We are layering the tin
roofing just like you would
when putting up
an actual tin roof,
but we're doing it
inside of the structure.
What we could do is
kind of leave it open,
and then when it gets crazy,
all we got to do is boop-boop.
That way we can stand
around, you know?
Stack 'em in there.
-There you go.
If we need 'em,
then they're in there.
Those fish look so good!
They're, like,
smoke-cooked right now.
-Good job, team!
-Well done!
-Internal roof.
-That's new.
You let me know if
you need help, Teal.
During the night, we
had to get panels in place
when the wind got really bad.
That's hard to do in the dark,
but honestly, it's harder to do
when everybody's just
talking a lot, especially Joe.
That was probably
more frustrating
than the task itself.
Teal is great, but
during the high winds,
she snapped at me.
I tried to give her a light,
and she yelled at me.
You know, I was
really surprised.
And I feel like
that's not conducive
to what this group
is here to do.
Not good.
So this morning, as I'm
trying to get the pot to boil,
I noticed that the flies are
all over the smoked fish.
Smoking anything
that's that thick
takes a lot of tending,
because not only do we
have the flies out here,
but just the air temperature
out here is really quick
to spoil anything.
How's that stuff coming?
I'm trying to keep
these flies off of those.
-Ooh, that stinks!
-Not good.
-Smell it.
-No, I don't want to.
Do we need to just lower it?
I think that one's done.
So now you could... Ooh.
Oh, yeah.
As soon as I squeeze
it, I immediately know.
It feels like it's got a
bunch of air bubbles in it,
and I'm like, "Oof," I
could smell it right then,
and I'm like,
"Yep, they're bad."
Bring it to somebody
else's attention, not mine.
I don't wanna be the one
that makes that decision.
Yeah, I'll make
it, no, it's done.
There's no decision to be made.
I was told just
to dry 'em whole.
With four days left, I do
not wanna be removed
from this challenge
with stomach issues.
Vomiting, diarrhea,
and all of that
is not only a quick way to
get extremely dehydrated,
but that's a type of sickness
that I don't think my body
can handle at this point.
So them four catfish
are toast, dude.
-I mean, they're rotten.
-Smoked ones?
-The smoked ones?
Yeah... squeeze
them, you'll see bubbles
come out the spine
holes, and it reeks of rot.
-Really?
-Really, really.
They should have
been stripped, deboned.
That sucks!
That surprises the out of me.
Yeah, they're probably too high.
I just think they
weren't opened up.
Yeah.
I was wondering how
that was gonna work.
I've never seen a
whole fish smoked.
Man, I've done it a few times.
Maybe they were too high.
They hung the fish
up the wrong way.
They needed to be deboned.
You know, you could
leave 'em on the head.
You just gotta cut that
backbone out and use sticks
to keep the fillets apart.
That turned out
to be a bad move.
Oof!
When everybody realized
the four fish were spoiled,
it really was a huge problem.
Maybe I dropped
the ball on that.
So now I'm worried about
putting more food on the table.
Well, we can do
another chain gang.
-Yeah.
Are you ready? You ready?
I'm ready.
Let's go get some
fish out of the water.
And now we have to think
about the chicken wire.
We could think give
it another run today
and see if we can
get some more food.
There are lots of
catfish moving around
in that pond still.
Should we just
stretch it out a bit?
Yeah, let's stretch
this whole thing out.
So we've got the poultry
wire from the slaughterhouse.
This is rusty and falling apart.
There's holes that are
beginning to get much bigger.
I remember there was
one spot where we had
a couple of big ones
get out, just like a rip.
Look at this.
Right here. This is only
joined on by a
couple of bits of wire.
-Look at this, Steven.
-Oh, my God!
This is the gap I was
trying to hold close.
Well, that'll never work.
Nope.
Can't believe
this! This is crazy!
Yeah, that's nuts!
The chicken wire's
too skinny, and it's kind
of off the table today.
But it's still important
to work on getting
protein sources other ways.
We need everybody
to help us do that.
I'll go hunt.
Slay it, darling.
-You too, Joe.
-Thank you, Frank.
Good luck.
Hydrate up.
Yeah.
I know.
I don't even know
if she's gonna hunt.
I think she's
gonna sit in a blind
so she doesn't have
to be with us all day.
-Yeah.
-That's why she brought her mosquito net.
I don't know what's
happened with Teal,
but Teal's been
great as a partner.
You know, we've been
together since day one.
-Oh, Miss Teal.
-Oh, sir.
-I got you a prezzie!
-That is so awesome!
She's happy to just
keep working away,
keep chipping away at the
jobs that need to be done.
-There we go!
-That's...
Whoo!
That's what I'm talking about.
So this is very different
to see her in this space,
but being in such a
tough environment
with an apocalyptic
challenge like this,
there's no words
that can describe
what your body goes
through and especially
what your mind goes through.
She got a bit of an
anger out last night At Joe.
At one in the morning
when she started
screaming at Joe.
Joe, yeah.
Maybe all that
pent-up just came out
-and she's back to normal.
-Yeah.
Having eight
survivalists inside a cell
when you have no personal space
is like the most miserable
conditions possible.
The fact that I'm starving
and energy depleted in general
makes that kind of
situation even harder for me.
So, for me, I really need
to find a way to recharge.
I decided to see if I
could sneak up on them,
but they... they're
very, very smart,
and I couldn't get
within 40 yards or so.
Time to head back.
Unfortunately.
Jesus.
You know, this challenge,
it's been just a emotional,
mental, physical roller coaster,
starting off in the
complete burnt desolation.
This is like a death march.
Surviving there for 22 days,
you know, 17 of them on my own.
Starting to get
a little blackout.
It's incredibly difficult.
But what I know about
myself is I've got more in me.
Keep away, mother.
Now, this group has been
probably the best thing
that happened on
this challenge for me.
Son of a bitch!
Ugh!
Ran into some elephants,
and the wind was blowing
towards them so
they could smell me.
And we just keep crossing paths.
I'm taking every single
chance that I can get out here
just to make sure I'm in
a position where I could
have an opportunity
to shoot and gain a kill.
Again, elephants are
getting in the way of success.
It really sucks.
Is that my naked
family over there?
-Any action?
-Nothing new.
-I gotta just keep trying.
-Every day.
-Hydrate up.
-No, I don't want to.
The sun's popping off,
so definitely hydrate.
-You get some water?
-No.
-You sure, Teal?
-Said "no, thanks."
For whatever reason, I
feel like every time I get back
to camp just makes
my skin crawl.
I just feel like it's
the same story
every day, I feel
like I'm imprisoned.
Not sure what's going
on with Teal right now.
You know, she's
rude, really impolite.
She turned into a person
that I really don't recognize.
Yeah, I feel like she's just
constantly waging a war
-in her head right now.
-Yeah.
It brings the morale
down of the entire group.
Definitely.
Honest to God, man, like,
if she doesn't figure this out,
I can't imagine it's
gonna be healthy for her.
It's gonna be a cooker today.
-Yeah.
-You feel it?
I know. It's hot.
I'm going to hunt.
All right, Teal. Well,
good luck out there.
-Thanks.
-Good luck.
-Send in mojo your way.
-Perky's a strong word.
-Yeah.
When it comes to the
end of these challenges,
people go about their
emotions in different ways.
But we're days away
from leaving this place,
and I need everybody
in the right head space,
body space, mind space,
soul space to make sure
that we cross that
finish line together.
She's using all the coping
strategies that she has
to get through this,
but I feel like she's just
fighting herself every day.
I saw some egg nests,
so I'm gonna go and see
if I can get those down.
See if maybe they
have eggs in them still.
The people around me
are making me crazy.
It's just hard.
It's always just hard.
These are the nests.
They hang like that.
As you can see in
this one right here,
there are no eggs... of course.
Whew!
Lordy, lordy.
All right.
I got some water hole up here.
See what kind of signs there.
Got some fresh duiker
tracks, some warthog tracks.
So yeah, I think this is
a good spot for a blind.
After five weeks of
surviving in this wasteland,
getting food now is
more critical than ever.
I'm worried about escape
and getting to that finish line.
Teal is definitely
struggling the most out here.
I know what an amazing,
resilient woman she is,
but she's gonna have
hang on to the end.
She needs some protein
or something to eat.
Then that's exactly
what I'm gonna do.
Get another kill for
my team and myself.
Here we go!
So I got a shade
right here, a good view
of the watering hole.
So this is gonna
be home for a while.
I'm gonna hunt this right here.
All right.
You can feel that heat.
As a team, you know, we
got real camp dynamics now,
and people are struggling.
And for me, I think that's
where the mental part
of this challenge comes in.
This is my third
time in South Africa.
Oh, the pain is so bad!
First time I was med-tapped.
On "Last One Standing,"
I left. I've got no food.
This is just terrible!
And that's really
haunted me for years.
Holy crap!
That's given me the
motivation to fight through all
the really tough times out here.
Holy.
All right, go!
Keep an eye out for that crow.
Yeah, I see him.
And I had a Black Mamba
one foot from my head.
He bites you and you're dead.
So if all that was for nothing,
that would be soul-crushing.
There's hippos in the
water, and there's me.
And I'm hoping that we
can see impalas, duikers,
kudu, anything, come
in within about 20 yards.
If that happens, we
got a real opportunity.
So I'll sit and sit quietly.
To not make it out of
this Apocalypse on Day 35
would be a feeling I
wouldn't wish on anyone.
Ah.
We have to eat,
but right now I don't
even feel like eating.
So exhausted!
It is an absolute
scorcher today.
This is...
the hottest day I
have ever experienced
in my 45 years of life.
The top of the water
feels like you're stepping
into a hot bath.
I don't even know
how to describe it.
This is probably
my hardest day yet.
The heat will take people
out faster than any wild animal
possibly can, so it's
hard to get words out.
Words are hard, I've
got cotton mouth like
five seconds after I
step out into the heat.
Time's ticking by, and I
haven't seen anything.
That sucks.
At this point, it's the
hottest part of the day.
Time to go back to
the shelter. Hydrate.
That's enough for now.
We really have to pay
attention to our hydration.
This late in the challenge,
your body is already hurting.
You know, it's in
basic starvation mode,
and it has been for a while,
so dehydration can send you
a downhill spiral.
Just missed a dove
over there, Waterhole.
It's been a long day.
I've been in this
blind for hours.
I need to get back,
get some water.
It's time to get a drink
and try to get another day.
Teal!
-What's happening?
-Not much.
Any action?
-Um, a lot of cool stuff, yeah.
-Yeah?
-I'll get some water.
-Cool.
All right.
-Hello, my love.
-Hey.
How was it?
-Fun.
-If you need water.
-No.
-OK.
That whole container
there is all water.
-Good.
-Oh, wow!
-The one outside.
-Oh, that big boy?
-Yeah.
-Hell yeah!
Thank you.
What did you see
out there, Teal?
-Bird nests.
-Nice.
Checked all the
nests, no eggs, though.
-All that jazz.
-You get some water?
I'm good, thanks.
Yeah.
No.
I don't know, something
is wrong with her.
And I don't think
it's a small thing.
She's like mentally
taking a cliff dive
and doesn't wanna
be around anyone
for any reason whatsoever.
We are all really,
really, really, really
concerned about Teal's welfare.
And I think it's really
important to have
a bit of a group chat
about the dynamic
and about how things
were going and basically
address our concerns.
So she hasn't
drunk water all day?
-Nope.
-Jesus.
She drank a little bit
this morning and that's it.
Teal's been on an
emotional rollercoaster,
but you've gotta
keep drinking water.
If you do anything
different to that,
you're gonna be out
of here quick-sticks.
It's absolutely concerning
to me that she's just
pulling herself back
from everyone a little bit.
You know, concerned
she's not drinking enough.
We offer her, you know, water.
She has like a sip a day
and that's not even close
to enough to what
you need out here.
Yeah, I don't understand
what's going on.
If she was just being
pissy for 24 hours,
-that's one thing.
-Yeah.
But this has gone on
for like three days now.
It's like a mental
health decline.
We're watching what we say
around, walking on eggshells,
which is unfair.
I'm seeing her go down
and it's very strange.
She's very dull
in her responses.
She just is very
harsh in her criticisms.
She's treading water out
here and it's dangerous.
This is a dangerous place
to be stuck in your own head.
Somebody needs to
have a conversation
because we can't
do it seven on one.
That's not fair.
Yeah, I'm happy to talk to her.
-OK.
-I don't know how it's
gonna land, but I'm happy to.
OK, cool.
I don't want her to go any
deeper than this, you know?
No more decline.
But I don't think she's
gonna make it to the end.
Yeah, agreed.
Yeah.
-Are you good?
-Yeah, I'm fine.
Teal's had a difficult
time since the merge,
so I'm gonna have a
chat with her one-on-one.
I am concerned for where
she might be mentally.
-Everyone's worried about you.
-Yeah.
I'm just tired of...
-Tired of everyone?
-Tired of just...
Tired of... My social
battery is empty.
Yeah, I get that.
But it's... for me, it's, um...
I just watched you
last couple days, like,
you're not drinking
a lot of water and.
Like, that's what
I'm worried about.
I get the social battery.
-I'm drinking water.
-Drinking enough?
Yeah.
So what I'm actually
worried about as well is
people are sort
of feeling like...
they're walking
on... having to walk
-on eggshells around.
-On eggshells?
-You know.
-About what?
One-word answers and
bit snippy and whatever.
-Oh.
-Like it's difficult
to be around you, sort of thing.
Oh.
-I just wanna...
-So like saying
I'm good when people
ask, that's not OK?
I gotta like tell
them something?
No, but I think
everyone just wants you
to be part of it,
and I get it totally.
I didn't realize people were
thinking I was being snippy.
I apologize.
I'll make a point to make
sure people know that.
OK.
I'll be honest, I'm exhausted.
I'm physically exhausted.
I don't have many pounds
left on my body to give.
Everybody's coping
mechanisms are different,
and these last few days have
been absolutely exhausting.
Escaping from here and
getting back to civilization
just sounds like such a dream.
For those of you
that are worried,
my social distancing has
nothing to do with anybody.
And nobody has to be
walking on eggshells.
And my one-word
answers are just mostly
because I'm tired of talking.
I'm honestly just exhausted.
If it's offended
anybody, my apologies.
But that's all it is, and
it has nothing to do
with anybody else.
And I'm sorry that
people are offended by it,
and I'm sorry that
it's bothering people.
Don't let it make you
feel uncomfortable.
I don't think we're
uncomfortable, Teal,
I think we were just
worried about ya.
There's nothing to
be worried about.
-I'm drinking.
-I know.
I'm still here boiling
water and doing stuff
-and collecting firewood.
-I understand.
I understand, I'm just telling
you how we were feeling.
It's just your distance.
We were just worried about
you because we do care
about you, and you are
an integral part of this team,
and we love you and
we care about you.
-It's all.
-I'm just exhausted.
We're not mad, we're not
upset, we were just worried.
Is all. That's the whole thing.
-No, I'm fine.
-OK.
Yeah, it takes a lot
of courage to do that.
-But we'll let you do you and... -OK.
-Thanks, Teal.
-Thank you, sweetheart.
-Yep.
At this point in this challenge,
your mental
stability and strength
is the most important.
Without it, you don't survive.
We got some cloud cover today.
That's not good.
It's definitely not
the perfect situation.
Escaping this Armageddon
is gonna take calories.
But since the fish were spoiled,
the hunting's still really hard.
Here, these cool days,
it's not good for hunting.
-No.
-You know, the animals
aren't dying of
heat stroke like us.
There's lots of moisture
on the vegetation.
Yep.
We will look at the
net. We'll start fixing it.
Clip the wires, overlap, and go.
I like it.
We haven't had any
luck so far with hunting,
and so fishing may be really
our only choice going forward.
We just do a clean cut here,
and like a clean cut there,
and just join them together.
Yeah, yeah, because
all this, this is good.
-This is all primed up...
-Yeah, this section down here
is looking pretty good, too.
They're each 10 meters,
so I got 20 meters of good.
Yeah, 60 feet?
Yeah.
There's a real bad section
in the middle of the net,
and we decided to
eliminate that completely.
We have to basically
patch it, cut old pieces off,
bring 'em over,
patch where the rip is,
just do a continuous
cycle of patching
where the bad spots are.
So it's a time-consuming event.
Boom.
-Yeah, save that if we can.
-...Yeah.
-It's like man sewing.
-They were ma... yeah.
These are the two of the best
male wire sewers in the world.
You're damn right.
There's no holes in that one.
-It is, isn't it?
-Yeah.
No holes anywhere,
double-strength in the middle
where they're hitting.
Yeah, super-strong, double-mesh.
Look at all these
fish in here right now.
Look at all that.
Get in my belly.
All hands on deck. Need
to lock it up, get some...
legit protein on the table.
One more good win
would give the whole group
a nice little boost,
especially Teal.
She's just struggling and weak.
Are we doing the same
thing we did the first time?
Little bit less panic
this time, I hope.
Yeah, we don't have
people jumping around inside.
No, we don't need people
jumping around inside.
-Yeah.
-The first day we were
-fishing with it, it was... -Grab it!
-Grab it!
...was just crazy and
everyone got excited.
It was a little bit of chaos,
so we're hoping to get
more controlled so that we
can finish this successfully.
We're gonna take our time.
Slow and methodical.
We have to get food,
because if we don't,
it's gonna be almost
impossible to make it to the end.
If we get food...
we might be screwed.
Oh... A light drag
on the bottom.
We're gonna kind of
bring in, like horseshoe.
This fishing technique
that I wanna do,
basically just set it down
deeper in the mud later.
That way we can
encompass a larger area,
come together
faster, and hopefully
not lose so many fish.
Hopefully it's
not too short now.
Yeah.
All right. We all
on the ground now?
Everyone just gonna
slowly push it forwards.
Just push it.
OK. There we go.
Hey, I'm gonna get up
here and pull this, OK?
-There you go.
-OK.
Move it up a
little bit, shuffle.
Like six inches at a time.
Oh, there they are.
There you go... Nope,
nope, nope, don't even...
We're not even
gonna grab nothing yet.
There's way too much space.
We just need to
keep 'em contained.
They're gonna start
testing this bit right here.
Yeah, OK.
Oh, one got out.
I'm just hoping that this
poultry wire holds up.
I don't want to let this go.
OK.
I've got big holes
over here, by the way.
Oh!
Want me to get that net
bucket and get in there
-so I can screw these out?
-Yeah, get that net.
-Yeah, yeah.
-Let's see.
I like the net bucket
idea. Let's try it.
It's right there,
man. I'll just grab it.
There we go. You're
not going to get out.
No, you're not.
Let's keep everything
down, it's calm and cool.
Keep it down.
This poultry net
is falling apart.
It's coming down
to the wire here.
Look at that. Get it, Frank.
-Yep.
-Ey!
There you go. Beautiful.
There's your new home.
-No!
-Yes!
Oh, no, no, no, no!
-Try to kick 'em!
-He's coming out!
Get the net!
Yeah, I like the
net bucket idea.
There you go. Beautiful!
-There's your new home.
-Beautiful!
-No!
-Yes!
Oh, no, no, no, no!
-Try to kick 'em!
-He's coming out!
-Kick him!
-OK.
Once again. It's all right.
That's right.
Gotta pinch that bottom corner.
Yeah, there you go. Now
you've got a proper scoop.
Get up there more. Yeah, there.
Feel, grab and toss! Beautiful.
-Nice.
-All right.
-Here, here.
-I got this one.
We fixed the nest. We
took out the big holes.
And this is actually working.
Hey, that's a good size!
This MacGyver
ability that we have,
using man made materials and
how they can be better utilized,
those catfish never
knew what hit 'em.
I love you guys. We did this.
This has got this
down to a science.
Not as dramatic, but
this is definitely getting
-greater yield here.
-There we go.
-Nice.
-Worked like a champ, bud.
-Good job, bud.
-Get it in there.
Get that corner.
They love that corner.
It's awesome. Watching
Teal participate,
she's eager to do
it, quick to jump in.
It's a really
positive team effort.
There he is! Yeah, two-fer!
Let's see, how many
do we have over there?
-Yeah, four.
-Six, seven, eight.
Can you already believe
that we're all gonna be
-eating an entire fish -already?
-Beautiful, beautiful.
This challenge has been
difficult in everybody's tribe.
Everybody had
difficulty getting food,
surviving the weather, the
environment, the animals.
And it really took us
all coming together
to this location to
problem solve as a team,
as a family, to overcome
these challenges.
-Mm!
-Big fat fishy hugs!
That's what "Naked
and Afraid's" all about.
Just chunk 'em on the grill.
We're not gonna be
smoking fish again.
Oh!
Looks like we're gonna
eat pretty good tonight.
That's a good feeling.
All right, guys. Cheers.
Cheers!
Cooked at perfection, Frank.
Mm.
That is so good.
We all got a big fat fish feast.
Now I'm like full of energy
and I wanna get out of here
and escape as soon as possible.
It is a hot one today.
Is there any water left?
I'm gonna hydrate so hard today.
It's less than 24
hours before you know,
we're all on foot making
our escape from this place.
Tomorrow, we're all walking
into something together
that we have no clue
what it is. This is an escape.
It's not an extraction.
And we don't know
what that looks like.
So it's just gonna have
to be we have to be
as prepared as possible.
The upcoming escape
is very much unknown.
And so we really
need to be drinking
as much water as possible.
Making a filtration
system is actually really,
really important.
So I'm just collecting some
stones for the top layer.
Next they're just gonna
get crushed into a powder.
I want most of the
pieces to be really dusty.
The most important
part of this whole thing is
that thick layer of charcoal.
I'm gonna use this piece
of polyester at the bottom
for the cotton.
I'm gonna make a
bunch of holes in this.
The metal container
that I'm using as a filter
I found at the mechanic's
house on day one,
and I've been looking forward
to using it this whole time.
OK, so that's, like,
a nice thick layer.
Just kind of make
sure it's set in there.
Just sprinkle it on.
Yeah.
Evenly, again, just so it...
Yeah, it's gonna be good.
OK, we got our big old filter.
That'll work.
The stones take
out large particulates.
Then you get into sand,
which does the last bit
of true filtration.
The charcoal neutralizes,
absorbs chemicals,
absorbs oils, and then
out the bottom you go.
-Oh, wow!
-Love it!
I'm feeling a little bit better.
Trying to truly find a way
to rise above all this disaster
and finish the challenge strong.
See, how cool is this?
Teal taught me how
to do a filtration system
for the water.
Teal brings with her
a wealth of knowledge,
so still completing the
apprenticeship of my life.
How good is it? It's
awesome, isn't it?
-Mm-hmm.
-So much better.
-I know.
-So happy about it.
-More?
-Yes, we should.
-We should never say no.
-That's our rule.
This has been a long journey.
It's been a good
one, but it's been hard.
So I'm making some just-in-case
shoes for when we escape
out of here.
The ultimate goal for me
is surviving South Africa,
and so there's zero chance of me
not finishing this challenge.
I'm going ahead and
making a little pack
of some essentials, fire
starter, some wires, cordage.
You know, this being
a brand new challenge
with this escape route,
it's never been done
in the history of
"Naked and Afraid."
So I don't know what to expect.
And that's scary.
You're not out of
a survival situation
until you're out of
the survival situation.
All right, now I
got a safe pack.
It's watertight,
miscellaneous wires,
whatever we need.
If an emergency
happens to pop up
on our escape out of here,
Imma have it right in here.
We're getting out of
here. It's time to escape
Oh, my God.
You wanna go take a piss?
Definitely not.
Holy.
That was so wild.
That was scary.
Last night in the Rage Cage,
there were several different
directions we heard
those hippos coming from.
It's time to go, and all of
us are eager to escape.
All right, guys,
putting out the fires,
then hit the road.
Woo-hoo!
We need to make sure that
we bring our knives, our bows.
I'll carry a pot of water.
We're definitely
taking four water pots.
You never know what's
gonna happen in the bush,
so we're gonna take
everything that we can
that's gonna be necessary
to escape this Hell on Earth.
Oh, Joe, Joe, Joe, Joe, Joe.
The Wheelderbeast has to stay.
I'm sorry, buddy.
He's reached the
end of his road.
It's kind of sad. You
know, I birthed that thing.
That was one of my
first MacGyvering,
and I've improved
it along the way,
and I would have
liked to have carried it
to the end, but, you
know, it's just not practical.
All right, everyone
almost ready?
-Yep.
-I just wanna
get everyone's mind
in the right mindset
before we go. There's
no one coming for us.
We need to find a way to
make it back to civilization.
With no extraction
vehicles awaiting them,
the survivalists must
make their escape on foot
by trekking over eight miles
deep into the thick brush
of hill country, to
a mountain range
on the northern edge
of the Wasteland.
If they can reach
the ridge line,
their escape route will
lead to a game ranch,
the closest inhabited outpost,
where a welcome
celebration is being planned.
This is a long way, guys.
You all need your
heads on a swivel.
We've still got
lions, elephants,
all that stuff out here.
There's not a cloud
in the sky today,
so it's gonna be a cooker.
With triple digit temperatures
and a total elevation gain
of over 1,000 feet, the
rocky terrain is covered
with sharp acacia thorns
and teeming with fire ants.
Lions lurk in the
bush as leopards prowl
from the trees and rocks above.
The area is also home to
the deadly gaboon viper,
whose two-inch fangs release
the highest amount of venom
of any snake in the world.
This is not gonna be easy. We're
gonna have to push. It's gonna be hard.
Just watch for
people dropping off.
Watch for people if
they look like they're
not drinking enough,
sweating too much, heat stroke,
that sort of stuff.
All right, we're gonna
do this as a team.
We're gonna do this as
a family to get out of here.
-100%.
-It's gonna be hard,
but we're gonna
make it work, yeah?
What hasn't been hard out here?
Yeah, exactly. One last push.
-That's all we're gonna do.
-...Slow, steady, stick together.
-All right.
Hands in. One, two, tree.
-Yeah!
-Armagettin' outta here.
-See you, Rage Cage.
-Peace out, home.
-Laters.
-Let's roll.
I'm so ready to
escape this place.
It's been one of the
hardest challenges
I've ever come across, I
know this escape is gonna be
one of the hardest things
I've ever done as well.
So long.
My muscles just being
atrophied and being worn out.
My body is tired,
so it's gonna take
everything I've got.
-It's starting to get hot.
-Yeah.
It's definitely Africa.
Heat came out.
We've still been
running on zero fuel.
We've had full
bellies from catfish,
but that's just protein.
Energy for the body
is carbs and fats,
and we've had none of those.
I hate to say it, but there is
still a risk that we could lose
someone on the hike out.
How you holding up, Wes?
I'm doing good, buddy.
-You doing all right?
-Yes, sir.
Good.
This sun is out,
and it is cooking us.
We have Waz in the
front setting the pace,
and I'm in the back making
sure nobody gets hurt.
Ah!
You all right?
Careful, that thorn's
really angry, eyeball-level.
-All right, thanks, Teal.
-Acacia.
Mm!
Ugh, that was a good one.
Just a full forest
of the devil's Legos.
-Oh, Jesus.
-Pretty rough terrain.
This thick bush, thorny,
probably full of ticks.
Lots of thorns up here,
guys, watch your step.
It's gonna be small and
tight, but we're going to do it.
Oh.
For sake.
Oh, please.
Doing all right?
We just gotta keep pushing.
Elephants have
definitely been here.
Oh, they knocked
that whole thing over.
The trail's thick.
Can't see very far.
There's no telling
what's in this landscape.
More worried about the
elephants than anything,
'cause they call
'em the gray ghost,
because when
you're looking like this,
you don't see 'em
until you literally look up
and their backs
break the skyline.
-Sun's hot.
-Yeah, it is.
Quick steps through
here, 'cause this is a big
ant colony. They will bite.
-Thorns and ants, guys!
-Oh!
-Damn, they're fast.
-Oh, my God!
These are angry
little don't they?
Oh, Jesus!
Yeah, they bite.
-Yep.
-Little.
For such, they pack a
punch for such a little thing.
Holy guacamole!
Ouch!
I don't think I've ever
done something this hard.
I've definitely never
made it this far on so little.
Still part of the
hero's journey.
That's right.
That sun is kicking.
I'm almost out of
water in this front one.
How we're looking at the back?
I've got more than half.
-OK.
Hey guys, I wanna get to
the top of the hill up here.
I'm pretty confident
we're gonna be able to see
the civilizations from up
here at this highest point.
Hey Waz, let us catch
up just a little, will ya?
Need a break. We need to stop.
Yeah.
Everybody get a
drink if you need it.
-No rush on that.
-Holy!
The heat and the dehydration.
All of these things are my vibe,
and we haven't even
got to the mountain yet.
That's the finish line
right there, boys and girls!
You can see it.
We've done 35 days
of pretty hard stuff,
-and all we've gotta do is this.
-That's it!
-Let's go!
-You good, Wes?
-Yeah, buddy, we're good.
-All right, guys,
Let's go, let's push
this. One last push.
We're gotta get out
of this wasteland.
-Oh, Jesus!
-You good, Teal?
Yeah.
Oh, man!
The terrain's getting
way more rocky.
Watch your ankles
on this stuff, man.
This is rolling,
breaking ankles.
-Feels real snaky here.
-Yeah.
They're here, that's for sure.
Thanks for pointing that out.
Oh, my God! There's so
many more thorns here.
Oh! Oy, oy, oy.
Yeah, this is ridiculous.
Elevation definitely
doesn't help.
Oh, God.
Hanging in there, Wes?
Ah, legs are burning!
For someone to succeed
in "Naked and Afraid,"
you have to have
mental fortitude,
and you have to
have a desire to finish.
But make no
mistake... it is brutal.
I'll never give up,
but I don't know how
much more I can take.
This walking isn't
getting any easier.
Oh. Oh, gosh.
I mean, I don't know
how much more, I mean.
This challenge has been
the most unbearable thing
I've ever done in my life,
but I got too much at stake.
I'm almost done.
I can taste it. I can feel it.
And we are ready to
get the hell outta here.
Hey, guys, I'm out of
water in this first can here.
Do we have much
left, or what's going on?
I got about a swallow left.
-All right.
-Jesus Christ.
That sucks.
This escape pod is
one of the hardest things
that I've done.
There's so much uphill.
Every time I look up,
there's just more and more
hill in front.
We're running out of water.
I don't know if we're
all gonna make it.
This is killing me.
Oh, God. I can't.
Oh.
-Oh, my gosh.
-The sun is kicking.
Oh, I don't know
if I can make it.
Oh, you guys are so...
-Oh.
-...Let's keep pushing, keep pushing!
One foot in front
of the other, guys.
-Keep pushing.
-OK.
-We got this!
-Oh, yeah.
Strong work,
team. Not long left.
We're up on the
crest of the hill,
so I'm not sure what
more we got in store,
but my mouth is
dry, I'm out of water.
Feel like I can't take
any more steps. Oh.
Just keep pushing.
Keep pushing, Teal.
Do you see anything, Waz?
Looks like we got a
clearing up here, guys.
-No way, really?
-We got an opening?
Oh, God, I hope so.
Guys, there's
something down here.
There is something down here.
That's not nature.
-Guys, look at this!
-What the...?
I hear music!
I can see people.
Holy crap!
Look at this!
-What is this?
-What!
-You guys!
-Hello?
Oh, my God!
You know, I've completed
a lot of challenges.
Usually it's an
airplane or a helicopter
or, you know, a truck,
but there's traditional
African song and dance?
It's awesome!
I've heard no music for 35 days.
And I see a barbecue going on.
I smell food.
-Yeah! What?
-Whoo!
Now that is a welcome sight.
To see friendly faces and
hear laughter and music
is overwhelming for the
senses, and I don't really know
-what to make of it.
-Did we die?
We've died and gone to heaven.
After surviving the apocalypse,
coming back into civilization,
it was more confusing
than anything.
It's a crazy feeling!
I don't even know what to do!
Give me some food.
Can I have some of that?
Humanity still exists.
We're done, we've escaped
this hellhole of a bush.
Oh, my God... fat!
-Nice.
-That's the first fat I've seen in 35 days.
Look at that drip.
You know, I come out
here to test my skills
for a doomsday situation,
and, you know, I nailed it.
I did my best to provide
food for the team.
You know, people like us,
we just kinda do what we do,
and we're not hoping
for a doomsday situation,
but we're always ready for one.
I normally have more
manners than this.
I apologize now.
Give me some of this fruit.
Oh. Oh, fruit!
We went from Hell
all the way to paradise.
And it feels good.
Thank you.
Good job, man. Way to
be a great team member.
Well done, bro.
We did.
I came here to do
battle with South Africa
and come out successful.
And it's my first
Africa completion
in the harshest
apocalyptic environment
you could ever think up.
And so I'm super proud.
-Oh, my God.
-Holy.
I don't even know
what to say at this point
because I feel like I
entered as one person
and emerged as something
completely different.
I think coming
into this challenge,
I was more a survivor
than a survivalist.
And now I realize that,
if I survived
Africa for 35 days,
I can survive anything!
Come on, you made it! I'm happy.
Oh, God, you're gross.
-Ah, way to ruin a good moment.
-Whoo!
I'm really proud of
Teal, proud of how far
she pushed herself
through a lot of adversity, too.
She did it her way, she
dug deep when she had
to dig deep, and she made it.
It was a beautiful
thing to watch.
Hey, Team Thunder Bome.
We made it, the only
team to make it in the end.
-Only team!
-I love you guys.
My original team, Lex and Frank,
have impressed me so much,
and I don't think we
would have got through it
if we wouldn't
have been together.
-yeah.
-Cheers up... meat up.
-Meat up!
-Whoo!
We problem-solved as a team,
and watching them succeed
is amazing, and I
absolutely feel blessed.
-Yeah!
-Whoo!
I did 17 days alone
trying to endure the hell
that's been this apocalypse.
I suffered as an individual
and I thrived as a
member of a group,
and I think that's
the biggest lesson
that I can come out
of in survival here.
With a group like this,
this group is undefeatable.
There we go, there we go!
Many people believe
going into the apocalypse
that they'll just self-confine
and board yourself
in your house.
But I did learn that's
really not thriving.
What we were able
to accomplish together
was far superior to
anything that I ever imagined,
and I'm grateful for that.
We had to adapt
our survival skills
on an ongoing basis.
They had to be fluid.
They had to be dynamic.
Everything's gonna
change around you,
and you have to be able
to change and adapt with it.
If you don't, you're
not gonna make it.
I'm glad that after this,
I'm definitely more prepared
for a situation like that,
and I pray that
it never happens.
But if it does happen,
the King will definitely
-get through it.
-Way to go, team!
"Naked and Afraid!"
Whoo!
First shower. Look at my feet.
And that is why I
always bring one of these.
This is me, frying up
some liver with onions.
Yummo!
-Ah!
-Welcome to Africa.
After battling the barren
wasteland for 35 days...
There we go.
...the survivalists
bodies paid a serious toll.
Mopane moth.
Spending half the
challenge alone...
I'm gonna roast it
and I'm gonna eat it.
...Joe's extra workload
and limited calories
led to a loss of 62 pounds.
Good gosh.
Working at a calorie deficit
for most of the 35 days...
You know you're hungry
when you're picking
through some animal's
crap to find something to eat.
...Wes finally finished
a challenge in Africa
and, in the process,
lost 36 pounds.
Oh, wow!
Entering the challenge
as a vegetarian...
Family dinner of
scorpion shish kebab.
...Alexa made the
necessary choices to survive.
-Mm.
-That was weird.
And still escaped the challenge
with a total loss of 31 pounds.
To see weight loss results
for all of the survivalists,
visit
Facebook.com/NakedandAfraid.
I am so excited to get clean!
Woo-wee!
35 days! I haven't seen myself.
I look an absolute treat.
I'm a little...
little skinny, and very tan.
35 days
in the hardest challenge
I've ever been to.
Just got out, got in the room,
haven't even showered yet.
But I'm feeling really strong.
First shower after Africa.
Look at my feet.
And that
is why I always
bring one of these.
Brillo pad. No Brillo pad.
"Naked and Afraid"
tips and tricks.
Headed home!
Just a quick 22-hour trip.
-Who's that?
-Hey, girls!
-Hello!
-Who is that?
I missed you. Yes,
yes, good girls.
Well, I did it.
Took me five years to
get back to South Africa,
but I did it.
And in the most
hellish landscape
that you could
possibly survive in.
And if a real apocalypse
comes, you can believe
I'll survive that too.
I don't know what I expected
the apocalypse to teach me,
but I'm pretty sure it wasn't
to have a love of red meat.
This is me.
I'm frying up some
liver with onions.
Yummo!
Mmm.
Oh, my God!
This is honestly an absolute
life-changer for me.
When we're out there,
it was scorching hot,
and now all I
have to do is this.
I have to just press this
one button right here,
and I'll say, "70?"
I don't think so.
We're on 68! Let's go!
There's one thing I miss so
much from when we've escaped
the apocalypse and being
back to reality, is wriggly tin.
So, at my survival school,
I've got a new
container on site,
and I've put a roof
on it, wriggly tin.
I cannot get away
from this stuff.
This here helped me a lot
when I was on the apocalypse.
The king has bought a
castle, and not only a castle,
the house that I
actually grew up in.
I have been
renovating, remodeling.
While doing all this, I've
learned that a majority
of the tools around your house
would work incredibly perfect
for an apocalyptic situation.
Mini chainsaw!
Everybody during the
apocalypse should have
one of these. I'm just saying.
After being in Africa,
it's good to be back home
seeing stuff like this
in your own damn yard.
And a good size at that.
Every day, I'm just
grateful I'm back
from that African hellhole.
This is what I love to do,
and... Oh! You see that?
He tried me.
We'll get him in
this cooler here,
get him some place safe.
That's why it's always
important to have
a good cooler with
you or a bucket.
Hey, it's Joe, and I'm
back in my normal life,
except my normal life looks
a whole lot different now.
Because of the challenge,
because of what I faced,
and what I came to
understand about sustainability
and the apocalypse.
I quit my government
job of 20 years,
and now I own a feed store.
It's something that's been
a part of the community
for 40 years, and it
was gonna shutter,
so I threw my hat in,
and they took my offer,
and now that's what
I'm gonna be doing.
I'm gonna be providing that
service for our community.
I'm gonna be educating
people on some homesteading
and just some self-reliance,
and that's something
that this challenge has
really brought for me
because this world is precious.
It's a beautiful place,
but at any minute,
it can change.
Going out into the
unknown and being met
with that barren wasteland
was definitely the hardest part
about this challenge.
I was astonished
with my capability
when there's really
no other choice,
and that is what
survival is about.
You just have to get out alive.
End of the world? I got you!